Zac Klammer

x zklamm.github.io zklamm@gmail.com Corpus Christi, TX

SUMMARY

I'm an experienced software engineer comfortable with back end, front end, or managing cloud services (AWS). I recently created Maestro, an open source framework for serverless orchestration. Prior to working in software, I was a mechanical engineer working in the energy industry.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Co-founder & Software Engineer, *Maestro* 🖸

Jun 2020 – present

An open-source framework for rapidly deploying and iterating on serverless workflows using AWS Step Functions, AWS Lambda, and AWS IAM

- Built easy-to-use CLI that abstracts away complex deployment logic, downloadable as an NPM package
- Optimized speed of workflow deployment and teardown by leveraging AWS SDKs and designing Maestro to execute commands asynchronously
- Created common templates for AWS Step Functions with the declarative, JSON-based Amazon States Language
- Wrote custom retry/backoff logic to ensure Lambda functions and state machines were created with proper roles
- Co-authored technical case study that explores the area of serverless orchestration, existing solutions in the problem space, and the process of creating Maestro maestro-framework.github.io ☑
- Collaborated daily with a 100% remote team

Software Engineer, Baytek International

Jan 2019 - Feb 2020

- Built Microsoft Word plugin for creating product analysis templates using Visual Studio Tools for Office
- Restructured user roles of company's core software offering to provide more granular permissions
- Assisted with integration of third party gas chromatograph software

Full Stack Web Developer, Self-Employed

Aug 2017 - present

Built several open-source projects using technologies such as React, Redux, Rails, PostgreSQL, HTML, and CSS

- Reaction: A Trello-like application built with a React and Redux front end and Ruby on Rails back end
- Postit: A Reddit-like application built with Rails and PostgreSQL deployed to Heroku
- Airline Routes: An application that allows users to view and filter airline routes on a clickable SVG map

Project Manager & Mechanical Engineer, Southcross Energy

Mar 2014 - Aug 2017

• Managed multi-million dollar projects from initiation to completion

TECHNOLOGIES

Back End

- Node.jsRubv
- Rails
- Sinatra
- C#
- SQL

Front End

- JavaScript (ES5 & ES6+)
- React/Redux
- iOuerv
- Handlebars.js
- HTML/CSS

Cloud

- AWS Step Functions
- AWS Lambda
- AWS IAM
- Heroku

Other

- HTTP
- REST
- OOP
- Git/GitHub

EDUCATION

Software Engineering, *Launch School* □

2017 – 2020 | Remote

An online school that teaches software fundamentals with a Mastery-Based Learning pedagogy launchschool.com/employers

Bachelor of Science - Mechanical Engineering, *Texas A&M University*

2008 - 2013 | College Station, TX

ORGANIZATIONS

Agape Ranch, Respite Care Provider

2018 – present